<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Learning to build awesome cool stuff!]]></title>
  <link href="http://stark-coast-3432.herokuapp.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://stark-coast-3432.herokuapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-03T17:39:37-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://stark-coast-3432.herokuapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack Nolan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day One]]></title>
    <link href="http://stark-coast-3432.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/10/03/day-one/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T15:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://stark-coast-3432.herokuapp.com/blog/2012/10/03/day-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the first day of our development school in NY our teacher decided to go with a nice easy activity, creating 20ish branches on the school website git project and everyone edit your profile page. Well more a trial by fire then an ‘easy’ task ;). We worked in groups of four our team took a very collaborative approach creating one git branch and all working on it together. Considering most of us had a very limited grasp on css, html, git workflow and git commands.  We all had watched roughly an hour of video on each these subjects in the pre-work and on day one had to use them. As to be expected when you have 20ish branches on a single project almost all managed by people without real git experience we&#8230; ran into a few issues, although it was better than expected! We stayed a bit late and got it all ironed out eventually (favorite commit message of the night “please go away!” -Avi) it was a great experience and helped to remove some of the jitters you experience when you run your first git commands (you’re sure this won&#8217;t destroy everything?&#8230; You&#8217;re sure right?). Tomorrow we will go over the individual styles we created and decided on one to go with as a class!</p>

<p>Things we worked on,</p>

<ul>
<li>git workflow</li>
<li>git conflict resolution (lots and lots of this)</li>
<li>html</li>
<li>css</li>
</ul>


<p>Code selection(s) of the day:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>git checkout “branchname”
</span><span class='line'>git rebase master
</span><span class='line'>//fix conflicts
</span><span class='line'>git checkout master
</span><span class='line'>git merge “branchname”</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
